Guide to the Hester Lynch Piozzi Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Hester Lynch Piozzi collection
1776-1930
GEN MSS 125
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.2
(1 box)
Contains letters from Piozzi to various people, including Thomas Cadell, William Augustus Conway, and Penelope Pennington; one letter from William Seward that is addressed to Henry Thrale but written to Piozzi; and a manuscript version of Piozzi's poem, "The Three Warnings."
Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ongoing collection of documents acquired by gift and purchase from various sources. Type of accession (gift or purchase) and date of acquisition is noted in the box and folder list. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
This finding aid encompasses accessions of single manuscripts and small groups of manuscripts and other papers, by or pertaining to Hester Lynch Piozzi, which the library has chosen to group and list as an artificial collection.
Three warnings; Cadell, T. (Thomas), 1742-1802; Conway, William Augustus, 1789-1828; Pennington, Penelope; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; Seward, William, 1747-1799; Thrale, Henry, 1728-1781
- Correspondence, Series I
  - LETTERS FROM HESTER LYNCH PIOZZI
    - ALS to Mrs. George Anson Byron, Streatham, [England], 1790 Nov 10 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Scope and Contents
      Removed from: Bibliography of Byron from T. J. Wise.
    - AL in the third person to [Thomas] Cadell, [London?], 1788 Dec 19 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Gift, 1948.
    - ALS to William Augustus Conway, 1820 Jan 5 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Removed from: Retrospection by Hester Lynch Piozzi (London, 1801). Purchase, 1943.
    - ANS to Sir James Fellowes, 1815 Dec 6 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Containing an impromptu autograph poem on the year 1815. Gift, 1948.
    - ALS to William Dorset Fellowes, Penzance, 1820 Aug 31 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Purchase, 1943.
    - ANS to Mrs. William Fellows, 1816 Feb 10 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Removed from: Letters to and from the Late Samuel Johnson by Hester Lynch Piozzi (London, 1788). Purchase, 1943.
    - ALS to Samuel Johnson, Bath, [1776?] May 16 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Gift, 1992.
    - Transcript (typescript) by A. Edward Newton of Piozzi's ALS to Samuel Johnson, [1776?] May 16, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Bound volume with bookplate of A. Edward Newton and holograph note regarding Piozzi's letter. Gift, 1992.
    - ALS to Samuel Lysons, Edinburgh, [1789] Jul 21 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Gift, 1937.
    - ALS to Penelope Pennington, 1789 Apr 3 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      With added note by her husband, Gabriel Piozzi. Gift.
    - ALS to Penelope Pennington, London, 1802 Jul 16 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Purchase, 1961.
    - ALS to Anna Pole, Denbigh, Wales, [1799?] (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - ANS to Robert Ray, Leicester Fields, 1807 Apr 20 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Invitation to call. Purchase, 1935.
    - ALS to Miss Willoughby, No. 10 Lion Row Clifton, 1821 Mar 16 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - ALS to an unidentified recipient, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - ALS (fragment) to an unidentified recipient, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Gift, 1977.
  - LETTERS TO HESTER LYNCH PIOZZI
    - Seward, William, 1747-1799. ALS, London, 1780 May 14 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Addressed to Mr. Henry Thrale but written to Mrs. Thrale. Removed from: Retrospection by Hester Lynch Piozzi (London, 1801). Purchase, 1943.
  - THIRD PARTY LETTERS
    - Fellowes, Orlando Butler. ALS to Percival Merritt, Worthing, Sussex, 1930 Feb 3 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      With envelope. Accompanied by a copy, in Orlando Butler Fellowes' hand, of portions of four letters: 2 from Hester Lynch Piozzi to her executors, Merton-Super Mare, 1819 Oct 18 and Penzance, 1820 Oct 10; 1 from William Augustus Conway to Sir James Fellowes, Bath, 1821 May 7; 1 from Sir James Fellowes to William Augustus Conway, York Hotel, 1821 May 8. Removed from: Love Letters of Mrs. Piozzi (London, 1843). Purchase, 1943.
- Other, undated; Series II
  - Piozzi, Hester Lynch. "The Three Warnings", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Manuscript copy of poem in an unidentified hand, with a manuscript note by Sir William Fellows concerning the original. Purchase, 1943.
  - Engraving entitled "Mrs. Piozzi", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    "Sir J. Reynolds Pinx." "H. R. Cook fc." Gift, 1937.